Where monsters go to get away from it all.
Hotel Transylvania is a animation, comedy, family
film directed by Genndy Tartakovsky.
Welcome to Hotel Transylvania, Dracula's lavish five-stake resort, where
monsters and their families can live it up and no humans are allowed.
One special weekend, Dracula has invited all his best friends to
celebrate his beloved daughter Mavis's 118th birthday.
For Dracula catering to all of these legendary monsters is no problem but the party really
starts when one ordinary guy stumbles into the hotel and changes everything!
Count Dracula (voice), played by Adam Sandler.
Jonathan Loughran (voice), played by Andy Samberg.
Mavis Dracula (voice), played by Selena Gomez.
Frankenstein (voice), played by Kevin James.
Eunice (voice), played by Fran Drescher.
Wayne (voice), played by Steve Buscemi.
Hotel Transylvania is a 2012 American animated monster comedy film directed by Genndy Tartakovsky, written by Peter Baynham and Robert Smigel, and featuring
the voices of Adam Sandler, Andy Samberg, Selena Gomez, Kevin James, Fran Drescher, Steve Buscemi, Molly Shannon, David Spade, and CeeLo Green.
It tells the story of Count Dracula, who is the owner of Hotel Transylvania,
where the world's monsters can take a rest from human civilization.
When the "human-free hotel" is unexpectedly visited by a human traveler named Jonathan, Drac must do everything in his power to prevent his daughter
Mavis and the other guests from finding out that a human has found their safe place, which may jeopardize the hotel's future and his career.
As a first-time feature director, Tartakovsky set out to make a film that used his background in traditional animation to implement the physics of 2D in
computer animation, inspired by the physical comedy of Tex Avery, and departing from the focus on realism that had become standard in CGI fare.
Hotel Transylvania premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 8, 2012, and was
theatrically released in the United States on September 28, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
It received mixed reviews from critics and  grossed $358
million against a budget of $85 million.
It was nominated for a Golden Globe for Best Animated Film.
The financial success of Hotel Transylvania launched a
multimedia franchise, including three sequels.
The film explores themes of hotel, witch, vampire, romance, love.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.